KATE EFIMOVA

JavaScript and Java developer

Email: <u>kate.efimova0@gmail.com</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/kefimochi</u> Twitter: <u>twitter.com/kefimochi</u>

CodePen: codepen.io/KateEfimova/

Cell Phone: (925) 326-8049

SUMMARY

A software engineer who has been learning Computer Science since 2016 and has been receiving hands-on experience in writing programs for more than two years. Focuses on pleasant user experience while also considering the time and space complexity involved in building a product.

LANGUAGES/EXPERIENCE

CSS/SCSS	HTML	Git
Photoshop	JavaScript	Chrome Dev tools
SASS	Java	C/C++

QUALIFICATIONS

Fast Learner

- Dramatically increased knowledge of English after moving from Russia to the United States. Hands on experience and diving deep into concepts is the best way to learn for me personally.
- Reading tech articles and listening to podcasts every day in order to enhance understanding of the field.
- Grasped Java concepts in just three days after being familiar with C++ in order to take Data Abstract and Structures class.

Frontend Development

- Passionate about implementing intuitive design for users to enjoy.
- Cares about what matters most to the users, such as responsive web-design, fast animations with no lags, short page loading time and much more.

Backend Development

 Implemented a small social network using a graph structure where users can log in, join the network, add friends, modify their profile as well as see a list of friends' friends.

Team Leader

- Took a leadership role in every group project that was given at the De Anza Computer Science department.
- Can easily find some common ground with every member of a team in order to motivate them to get the work done well.

EXPERIENCE

Small Social Network (2019)

Spent around twenty hours implementing a small interactive social network using a graph structure. The dictionary was created in order to store all the users where the name of a user would be a key and a value would be an object with another nested object that linked to the keys of friends. The Small Social Network has a variety of features like login in, joining the network, adding friends, modifying the user's profile as well as seeing a list of friends' friends.

https://github.com/kefimochi/CIS-22C/tree/master/Final%20Social%20Network%20Project

MDN Search Extension

(2019-present)

An MDN Search Extension for Google Chrome that simplifies user's experience whenever they want to use MDN docs.

https://github.com/kefimochi/MDN-Search

- Version 1 prototype available on CodePen
- Currently, MDN Search Extension is in beta development. So far it triggers the search field
 automatically whenever popup is open(through clicking or 'Ctrl+M' shortcut) and redirects the user to
 the MDN search page with their keywords.

De Anza Classes (2017-present)

Participated in the De Anza College Computer Science program for two years, while also enriching knowledge in general fields like psychology, business, and art. Got together with other two CS majors and together we would collab on projects as well as help each other if in need. Took a data structures class and currently taking an Advanced Java class.

- Had a cumulative 3.854 GPA at Homestead High School.
- Attended 45 hours of De Anza college classes and accumulated a 3.93 GPA.

Independent Web Development

(2016-present)

Developed various web pages, as well as discovered common coding practices through reading articles and tutorials on dev.to. Quickly grasped concepts of how well-developed web design looks like and implemented it on my own. Took a part in JavaScript 30, read more than a hundred articles on Medium, and listened to around 90-100 hours of tech-related podcasts. Build many features that can be used on websites, as well as practiced creating whole websites on my own like the Femochi's Colors project.

- Completed 466 freeCodeCamp challenges.
- Personalized every JavaScript 30 challenge in order to try imitating real-world projects.

Photoshop Designer

(2011-2016)

Used acquired Photoshop skills in order to produce web designs and avatars for people on beon.ru. Created an organized group with the co-founder where we would sell designs. The group quickly became popular for

the quality of products that were made by people involved. For a year remained determined to run the group after which the popularity of Beon fell that caused group members to slowly disappear.

- Sold a variety of designs to people who continued to "wear" my works on their blog pages for at least 3-4 months each.
- Gained valuable experience of how to remain determined since each design took around 5-6 hours to make, while a video-avatar could accumulate up to 12-13 hours of work due to frame-by-frame edition.